<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: business | knock.on_wood]]></title>
  <link href="http://ryanwood.github.com/blog/categories/business/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ryanwood.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-18T14:06:49-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ryanwood.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan Wood]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CoWork: The First Month]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryanwood.github.com/blog/2010/11/29/cowork-the-first-month/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-29T14:04:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryanwood.github.com/blog/2010/11/29/cowork-the-first-month</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I first saw "cowork" as a concept on a Twitter post a year or so ago. Not knowing what it was, it forced me to create a new mental category about work environments. I come from a pretty traditional work environment. For the past 10 years, I've worked in a fairly typical office space. It was owned (or leased) by the company by which I was employed. I had a private office with door. It was certainly better than the cubicles of my youth, but I never thought much about it. It was just the office that you had to go to each day as a part of the job.</p>

<p>In August 2009, I was informed that my "job" would be ending as all software development would be moving to the home office in Houston, TX. I was given three months notice. It was November 1st before I knew it and I was no longer employed. While searching for another job, I decided to ramp up <a href="http://sourcescape.com/">Sourcescape</a>, my then part-time consulting business. The economy had other plans. I couldn't find much work and there were no full-time jobs on the horizon.</p>

<p>Fast forward 10 months. It's September 2010, <a href="http://sourcescape.com/">Sourcescape</a> is gaining some momentum. I'm working in various places. Some days I'm at home, others are in coffee shops, and others are in <a href="http://www.amyadele.com/">my good friend's office</a> who graciously offered me some office space. I see through Twitter that <a href="http://coworkgreenville.com/" title="CoWork Greenville">CoWork Greenville</a> is expanding and taking applications for full and part-time spots. This got the wheels turning and I decided to learn more.</p>

<h2>Figuring it Out</h2>

<p>Was it just a place where people who were fed up with coffee shops go to work? What was the benefit? After all, I have some space to work at <a href="http://www.amyadele.com/">Amy Adele</a> for free. However, I was isolated and really missed working with other intelligent people in my field. Maybe I should check out <a href="http://coworkgreenville.com/" title="CoWork Greenville">CoWork</a> and see about coming down there a day or two a week.</p>

<p>It just so happened that the <a href="http://coworkgreenville.com/" title="CoWork Greenville">CoWork Greenville</a> open house for their new location was around the corner, so I decided to go and check it out.</p>

<p>What I found was some of what I expected and something that I didn't. It was a group of "web people" work worked in the same building, some working together, some independently, all growing their businesses. That, I expected. The surprise came when I realized that this was more than just a common work place. One of the overarching goals was to build a community of independents that could make an impact on each other and the greater Greenville community.</p>

<p>It's hard to nail down what that means or how it will play out, but it was something that I wanted to be a part of. It seemed clear that joining the community would be tough to do once or twice a week. Even though <a href="http://sourcescape.com/">Sourcescape</a> wasn't exactly in the place financially to justify the move, I felt like it was clearly where I needed to be. I took a leap of faith and signed a 1-year lease to become a CoWorker once the new location opened on November 1, 2010.</p>

<h2>The First Month</h2>

<p>The first week was a tough adjustment. Not only did I move to a new office, but I has just taken on a new client working with the great team at <a href="http://www.railsdog.com/">Rails Dog</a>. It has been a long time since I've been one of the the new kid on the block. It was clear that many in this group had been working together for a while. The recent move brought a few of us new guys to bring the CoWorker count up to 16.</p>

<p>It's always tricky navigating a new environment. So far, though, it's been well worth it. As providence would have it, I'm fortunate to sit next to the super talented Matthew Smith of <a href="http://squaredeye.com/">Squared Eye</a> fame. As I get to know each of the guys (and girl) at CoWork, I continue to be amazed at the graciousness, talent and depth that this group brings together. I count myself blessed to be a part of it.</p>

<p>I have little idea of the the future holds for <a href="http://coworkgreenville.com/" title="CoWork Greenville">CoWork</a>, or for <a href="http://sourcescape.com/">Sourcescape</a> for that matter, but I'm convinced that it is a journey worth taking and one that will continue to surprise me and bring a smile to my face.</p>

<p>If you're interested in seeing how things unfold, please join us on the journey. You can follow us <a href="http://twitter.com/cowork">@cowork</a> on Twitter or check out the <a href="http://www.flickr.com/groups/cowork/pool/with/5199226596/">CoWork photo stream</a> on Flickr.</p>

<p>As always, I'll occasionally blog <a href="http://ryanwood.com/">right here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
